<resources>
    <string name="app_name">LigoApp1</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="ligo_info_text">The Laser Interferometer Gravitational-Wave Observatory (LIGO) is designed to open the field of
 gravitational-wave astrophysics through the direct detection of gravitational waves predicted by
 Einstein\’s General Theory of Relativity. LIGO\’s multi-kilometer-scale gravitational wave detectors
 use laser interferometry to measure the minute ripples in space-time caused by passing
 gravitational waves from cataclysmic cosmic sources such as the mergers of pairs of neutron
 stars or black holes, or by supernovae. LIGO consists of two widely separated interferometers
 within the United States—one in Hanford, Washington and the other in Livingston,
 Louisiana—operated in unison to detect gravitational waves.
    LIGO is a national facility for gravitational-wave research, providing opportunities for the broader
 scientific community to participate in detector development, observation, and data analysis. The
 capabilities of the LIGO detectors have been improved by the recently completed Advanced LIGO project,
 which will increase the sensitivity and observational range of LIGO by a factor of 10, bringing 1000
 times more galaxies into LIGO's observational range.

 The design and construction of LIGO was carried out by LIGO Laboratory’s team of scientists, engineers,
 and staff at the California Institute of Technology (Caltech) and the Massachusetts Institute of
 Technology (MIT), and collaborators from the over 80 scientific institutions world-wide that are members
 of the LIGO Scientific Collaboration.

 The responsibilities of LIGO Laboratory include operating the LIGO detectors, research and developent
 aimed at further improving the capabilities of the LIGO detectors, research in the fundamental physics
 of gravitation, astronomy, and astrophysics, and public education and outreach. LIGO is funded by the
 U.S. National Science Foundation and operated by the California Institute of Technology (Caltech) and
 the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT).

 Although it is considered one observatory, LIGO is comprised of four distinct facilities across the United
 States: two gravitational wave detectors (the interferometers) and two university research centers. The
 interferometers are located in fairly isolated areas of Washington (LIGO Hanford) and Louisiana
 (LIGO Livingston), and separated by 3,002 km (1,865 miles). The two primary research centers are located
 at The California Institute of Technology (Caltech) in Pasadena, California, and The Massachusetts Institute
 of Technology (MIT) in Cambridge, Massachusetts
</string>

    <string name="grav_wave_theory">According to newtonian theory, gravitational effects propagate from place to place instantaneously. With the
    advent of Einstein\'s special theory of relativity in 1905, a theory uniting the concepts of space and time into that
    of four dimensional flat space-time (named Minkowski space-time after the mathematician Hermann Minkowski),
 a problem became discernible with newtonian theory. According to special relativity, which is the current guideline
 to the form of all physical theory, the speed of light, c = 3 x 1010 cm s-1, is the top speed allowed to physical
 particles or forces: There can be no instantaneous propagation. After a decade of search for new concepts to
make gravitational theory compatible with the spirit of special relativity, Einstein came up with the theory of general
 relativity (1915), the prototype of all modern gravitational theories. Its crucial ingredient, involving a colossal
 intellectual jump, is the concept of gravitation, not as a force, but as a manifestation of the curvature of
 space-time, an idea first mentioned in rudimentary form by the mathematician Ceorg Bernhard Riemann in 1854.
 In Einstein's hands gravitation theory was thus transformed from a theory of forces into the first dynamical theory
 of geometry, the geometry of four dimensional curved space-time.</string>

    <string name="ligo_facts_text">Gravitational Waves Are Ripples in Space-Time
    According to Albert Einstein\’s theory of general relativity, gravity is not a force reaching out through the universe. It\’s a bending
    of space-time. When an object accelerates, it distorts the space-time around it, and that distortion travels away from the source
    at the speed of light.

    Gravitational Waves Come from Really Heavy Objects
    So how massive an object are we talking about? The first proof that gravitational waves actually exist came from a binary
    pulsar—two neutron stars, each about the mass of the Sun, that orbit each other. The pulsars\’ orbit is gradually shrinking,
    so the pulsars are losing energy. That energy is exactly the amount that general relativity predicts that the pulsars would give
    off in gravitational waves.

    The Effect of Gravitational Waves Is Very, Very Small
    Since gravitational waves are a ripple in space-time, they cause the distance between two points to change ever so slightly. How
    slightly? LIGO must be able to measure distances as small as 10−19 meter. The proton has a radius of about 0.85 × 10−15 meter,
    or 10,000 times larger.

    Measuring Gravitational Waves Is Tricky
    To detect a change in distance much smaller than the proton requires great precision. Each LIGO installation is a laser
    interferometer made up of two underground pipes, each 1.3 meters (4.3 feet) wide and 4 km (2.5 miles) long, set in an L-shape.
    The inside of the pipes is a vacuum. When a gravitational wave passes through LIGO, one arm of the instrument gets longer and
    the other gets shorter. A laser beam is split in half, sent down the two pipes, reflected back, and then recombined so the two
    beams cancel each other out in destructive interference if there is no gravitational wave. If there is a gravitational wave, the beams
    won\’t cancel each other out. A 4-km long beam is still not enough to detect a gravitational wave, so the beams are bounced back
    and forth about 400 times so the light travels a distance of 1,600 km (1,000 miles).</string>

    <string name="black_hole_text">Click the button above to learn more about the black hole collision that lead to the detection of gravity waves</string>

</resources>
